[{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"1. In How the Mind Works, Steven Pinker controversially stated that this activity is evolutionarily-useless “cheesecake [for] our mental faculties.” Jerrod Levinson revived interest in the German Romantic debate on whether the ideal version of this activity is “absolute” or “programmatic.” Schopenhauer believed that the purest expression of “the will” was this art form. The full title of a Friedrich Nietzsche book claims to trace The Birth of Tragedy from the Spirit of this art form. Several ancients theorized a kind of this phenomenon made by “the spheres.” For 10 points, Pythagoras studied intervals to help explain what art form that Edgard Varèse (“va-REZ”) defined as “organized sound”? ","answer":"ANSWER: music [accept music of the spheres or universal music or musica universalis; prompt on art until read; prompt on sound or harmony or melody] <Philosophy> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"2. Components of this object were outlined by H II (“H two”) regions in the work of Walter Baade (“BAH-duh”), who used metallicity to define two “populations” contained within this object: disk type I and bulge type II. This object is orbited by an extremely luminous globular cluster called Mayall II (“two”). After this object was controversially deemed an “island universe,” the discovery of Cepheid (“SEFF-ee-id”) variables inside this object resolved the 1920 Shapley–Curtis Debate by proving that this object is not a nebula. Messier 31 designates, for 10 points, what spiral galaxy that will collide with the Milky Way in 4.5 billion years? ","answer":"ANSWER: Andromeda Galaxy [accept Messier 31 or M31 until read; accept NGC 224] <Other Science> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"3. A child requests the poet to “Pipe a song about” this animal in the introduction to a collection that Northrop Frye analogized to the mythical paradise of Beulah. In another poem, this animal wears “clothing of delight” and feeds “by the stream & o’er the mead.” That poem is often paired with a poem that asks “Did he who made” this animal “make thee?” A poem titled for this animal uses the couplet “He is meek & he is mild, / He became a little child” to allude to the coming of Jesus. That poem asks this animal, “Dost thou know who made thee?” For 10 points, name this animal described in a poem by William Blake that is often contrasted with “The Tyger.” ","answer":"ANSWER: lamb [accept “The Lamb”; prompt on sheep] <British Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"4. Description acceptable. Sparked by the treachery of Servius Sulpicius Galba, this region saw the “War of Fire” led by Viriathus. In this region, many Numantians committed suicide to avoid slavery after being besieged by Scipio Aemilianus. Quintus Sertorius fought a namesake guerilla campaign in this region, which was finally conquered by Augustus in 19 BC. This home to the Cantabrians was originally divided into “Ulterior” and “Citerior” portions by the Romans. Hannibal’s attack on this region’s city of Saguntum was the initial impetus for the Second Punic War. Both Trajan and Hadrian were born in, for 10 points, which region that includes modern-day Lisbon and Madrid? ","answer":"ANSWER: Hispania [accept Iberia or the Iberian Peninsula; accept Spain or Portugal; accept Hispania Citerior, Hispania Ulterior, or Hispania Tarraconensis; accept Hispania Lusitania; accept Celtiberia] <European History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"5. A scheme in which Nicolas Chedeville (“nee-ko-LAH shed-VEEL”) published music under the name of this composer resulted in his alleged Opus 13, entitled Il Pastor Fido. A catalogue of 826 of this composer’s works, including over 500 concerti, was created by Danish musicologist Peter Ryom (“RUE-yum”). This composer’s most celebrated work is often paired with his C major mandolin concerto. This composer often wrote for the all-female ensemble of the Ospedale Della Pieta orphanage-convent. The opening of his The Contest Between Harmony and Invention is a set of four concerti grossi each paired with a sonnet on changing weather throughout the year. For 10 points, name this “Red Priest” who wrote The Four Seasons. ","answer":"ANSWER: Antonio Vivaldi [or Antonio Lucio Vivaldi] <Classical Music> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"6. This constructivist termed the ability for a learner to focus on multiple aspects of a problem “decentration.” This scholar proposed that one’s peer group was the primary influence on one’s ethics in The Moral Judgment of the Child, which led Lawrence Kohlberg to develop his namesake ethical model. Assignment rubrics are often considered real-world examples of schemas, which are critical to this thinker’s genetic epistemology. This psychologist’s namesake educational programs limit material based on which of four cognitive developmental stages the student is in; those stages include the concrete operational and sensorimotor. For 10 points, name this Swiss child psychologist. ","answer":"ANSWER: Jean Piaget (“pee-ah-ZHAY”) <Social Science> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"7. Traditionally, this practice’s stages are based on the Rigveda’s hymn 10.85 to Sūrya. The recently repopularized gandharva form of this practice is one of eight varieties listed by the Manusmriti. This practice includes the tying of the mangala sutra and the jai mala ceremony. A participant in this practice may arrive on a horse, accompanied by his baraat. After undergoing this practice, women begin applying red sindoor powder to the part of their hair. Garlands are exchanged during this activity, whose participants walk around a fire seven times, making their vows in the presence of Agni. For 10 points, name this practice whose “arranged” variety is often facilitated by the parents of the bride and groom. ","answer":"ANSWER: Hindu marriage [accept weddings; accept vivāha or vivaah; accept kalyanam; prompt on saṃskāra] <Religion> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"8. Along with carbon and hydrogen, this element is found in selectride anion reducing agent. Herbert C. Brown discovered a reaction that, prior to oxidation, adds this element and hydrogen across carbon–carbon double or triple bonds to yield alcohols in an anti-Markovnikov fashion. Clusters containing this element can be designated closo-, nido-, or arachno- when applying PSEPT (“P-sept”) or Wade’s rules. This element’s trifluoride is considered “electron-deficient” due to its violation of the octet rule and is a common Lewis acid. An oxide of this element is combined with silica to form pyrex glass. For 10 points, name this metalloid whose atomic number is 5 and whose chemical symbol is B. ","answer":"ANSWER: boron [accept B until read] <Chemistry> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"9. Starting in the 1940s, labor unions in this country annually negotiated for higher pay and benefits in the “spring wage offensive.” This nation’s car industry increased production efficiency through the development of Just in Time practices. The collapse of this country’s asset price bubble in 1991 led to crippling economic stagnation during the Lost Decade, which its current government has attempted to reverse through “Abenomics” (“AH-bay-nomics”). By the 1970s, this nation had overcome damage caused by Allied attacks in World War II to become the world’s third largest economy. For 10 points, name this East Asian country home to companies like Honda, Sony, and Toyota. ","answer":"ANSWER: Japan [or Nippon-koku; or Nihon-koku] <World History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"0. This character compares stars to “a great number of little bells that knew how to laugh” in a book whose last chapter talks about the “loveliest and saddest landscape in the world.” This character kills caterpillars for a companion who lives under a glass globe. After leaving a home that contains volcanoes to heat his breakfast, this character dies of a snake bite. A book titled for this character opens with the narrator’s drawing of an elephant that was swallowed by a boa constrictor. This character talks about his life on asteroid B-612 with an aviator who crashes in the Sahara. For 10 points, name this royal character who titles a much-translated novella by Antoine de Saint-Exupéry (“ann-TWAHN duh SAN-teg-zoo-pay-REE”). ","answer":"ANSWER: the little prince [accept le petit prince; prompt on prince] <European Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"1. Victor Veselago hypothesized an inverse form of this phenomenon on materials with a negative index of refraction. This phenomenon produces spectral line broadening proportional to the square root of temperature. The transverse type of this effect was observed in the Ives–Stilwell experiment. One plus v over c, all times the starting frequency, is equal to the observed frequency in this effect. Measurements of the radial velocity of galaxies are affected by relativistic forms of this effect called redshift and blueshift. For 10 points, name this phenomenon that results in a change of pitch for a moving siren. ","answer":"ANSWER: Doppler effect [or Doppler shift; accept redshift or blueshift until read] <Physics> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"2. In this city, the window panels of a reflective glass tower designed by Henry Cobb were replaced after several fell onto the street. A white triangular tower and a dark cube of glass and steel comprise a presidential library in this city designed by I. M. Pei. Its City Hall is widely hated for its brutalist design. A college campus located just outside this city includes a building with a thin-shell concrete roof shaped like one-eighth of a sphere, Eero Saarinen’s (“arrow SAH-ree-nen’s”) Kresge (“KREZ-ghee”) Auditorium, as well as Frank Gehry’s Stata (“STAY-ta”) Center. For 10 points, name this city home to the John Hancock Tower and the John F. Kennedy Presidential Library, whose suburb of Cambridge is home to the campus of MIT. ","answer":"ANSWER: Boston <Other Arts> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"3. Prior to becoming a renowned architect, Alfréd Hajós (“HA-yohsh”) was inspired to participate in these events following his father’s death by drowning. Lavish donations from George Averoff funded renovations for the first of these events, stymying Ferenc Kemény’s proposal that it take place in Budapest. On the basis of being “impractical, uninteresting, unaesthetic, and incorrect,” women were excluded from the first of these events by Pierre de Coubertin, often considered their founder. At the first of these events, Spyridon Louis won an event inspired by the Pheidippides (“fye-DIP-uh-deez”) legend, the marathon. For 10 points, 1896 saw the first of which modern international sporting events in Athens? ","answer":"ANSWER: the Olympic Games [or the Olympics; accept Summer Olympics; accept the 1896 Summer Olympics in Athens; do not accept or prompt on “Winter Olympics”] <European History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"7. ","answer":"ANSWER: Hong Kong [or Hong Kong Special Administrative Region; or Hong Kong SAR; or Xiānggǎng; or Hēunggóng; or HK] <CE/Geo/Other/Pop Culture> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"5. The speaker of a poem titled for one of these locations claims, “Where from above the milder sun / Does through a fragrant zodiac run.” Godber delivers cream puffs in a short story titled for one of these places, which ends with a girl asking her brother, “Isn’t life–.” A poem titled for one of these locations describes “Annihilating all that’s made / To a green thought in a green shade.” Laura takes a basket of leftovers to Scott’s widow in a Katherine Mansfield short story titled for a party in one of these places. In a short story [emphasize] titled for one of these locations, Stephen Albert is killed by Yu Tsun. For 10 points, Jorge Luis Borges (“BOR-hays”) wrote a short story titled for what kind of place “of the Forking Paths?” ","answer":"ANSWER: gardens [accept “The Garden Party” or “The Garden of Forking Paths”; prompt on labyrinth] <World/Other Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"6. IRE-BP is the cytoplasmic isoform of one compound in this process. An input to this pathway can alternatively form a 3-hydroxy-3-methylglutaryl compound in cholesterol biosynthesis. Alpha-ketoglutarate and succinate are intermediates in this process, which reduces FAD to FADH2 in a step catalyzed by fumarase. This process starts after an input of pyruvate is converted to acetyl-CoA (“uh-SEE-till co-A”) yielding three NADH. For 10 points, name this phase of cellular respiration following glycolysis and preceding the electron transport chain, also referred to as the citric acid cycle. ","answer":"ANSWER: Krebs cycle [or tricarboxylic acid cycle; or TCA cycle; accept citric acid cycle until read] (The first clue refers to aconitase.) <Biology> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"7. During an attack led by this tribe, Adolph Metzger fought using his bugle before dying alongside 80 others in the Fetterman massacre. A coalition led by this tribe forced the permanent closure of the Bozeman Trail after winning Red Cloud’s War. In a later conflict, this tribe was targeted by the “sell or starve” policy to force them to cede lands promised to this tribe by the 1868 Treaty of Fort Laramie, including the Black Hills. Days after winning the Battle of the Rosebud, a force led by this tribe’s chief Crazy Horse wiped out a U.S. cavalry detachment led by George Custer at the Little Bighorn. For 10 points, name this Native American tribe of the Great Plains. ","answer":"ANSWER: Sioux (“soo”) [or Great Sioux Nation; or Seven Council Fires; accept Lakota or Dakota or Nakota] <American History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"8. Paul Durrenberger and Bob Quinlan have suggested that these people did not strongly associate the Sun with day and the Moon with night. A major source for these people’s cosmology is a poem whose title translates as “The Seeress’s Prophecy.” Myths from these people refer to three wells: a well of venom, a well of fate, and a well of knowledge. In these people’s creation myth, a cow and a giant are born out of fire and ice that mixes together in the cosmic void, Ginnungagap (“GIN-ung-uh-GAP”). These people divided the universe into nine worlds that were rooted together by the great ash tree Yggdrasil. For 10 points, name these people that called the earth “Midgard” and worshipped gods like Odin and Thor. ","answer":"ANSWER: Norse [accept vikings or Icelanders or Danes or Norwegians] <Mythology> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"9. A posthumous (“POSS-chuh-miss”) publication by this author is based on interviews with Cudjo Lewis, the last survivor of the Atlantic slave trade. This author of Barracoon is given a gravestone inscribed with “Genius of the South” in an Alice Walker essay about “Looking For” this author. Nanny marries off the protagonist of a novel by this author after she kisses Johnny Taylor under a pear tree. As she recounts her life to Pheoby Watson, a woman in a novel by this author describes her marriage to the mayor of Eatonville, Jody Starks. In a novel by this author, Tea Cake is bitten by a rabid dog and is shot by Janie Crawford. For 10 points, name this author of Their Eyes Were Watching God. ","answer":"ANSWER: Zora Neale Hurston [prompt on “Looking for Zora”] <American Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"0. A painting by this artist features a black ball in front of an archway opening onto a beach. In that painting by this artist, as well as in other paintings with the same title, strips of white paint mark the edges of canvases that blend into the background. This artist painted several works depicting a dark street lit only by a single lamp below a daytime sky. This artist of The Human Condition and The Empire of Light depicted a train emerging from a fireplace in one painting, and showed an apple obscuring the face of a man wearing a bowler hat in The Son of Man. For 10 points, name this Belgian surrealist whose painting The Treachery of Images states “this is not a pipe.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Rene Magritte [or René François Ghislain Magritte] <Painting/Sculpture> Bonuses "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Name this trumpeter whose brother Branford wrote music for his album Black Codes. He is currently the jazz director at the Lincoln Center. ","answer":"ANSWER: Wynton Marsalis (“mar-SAL-iss”) "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Marsalis’s oratorio Blood on the Fields was the first jazz work to win the music category of this prize, whose 2018 iteration went to Kendrick Lamar’s DAMN. Columbia University awards seven of these prizes named for a newspaper magnate. ","answer":"ANSWER: Pulitzer Prizes [accept Pulitzer Prize for Music] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"6. The Dixieland “tailgate” style of playing this instrument makes much use of its ability to play true glissandos. ","answer":"ANSWER: trombone [or slide trombone; accept tenor trombone or bass trombone; accept tailgate trombone] <Other Arts> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Name this conceptual person that titles Coventry Patmore’s most famous poem. This idealized portrayal of the perfect wife shaped household culture during the Victorian era. ","answer":"ANSWER: The Angel in the House [prompt on Angel; accept “angel in the home,” which is a lesser-used term] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Opposite the Victorian “angel” was the “woman” described by this adjective, who had lost her virtue via sex, alcohol, or a different vice. William Gladstone devoted much effort to “saving” these women, who often participated in prostitution. ","answer":"ANSWER: fallen women "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] In her Book of Household Management, the Victorian Isabella Beeton compared the wife to the “Household General,” who had to command these general household workers that included stewards, gardeners, and cooks. ","answer":"ANSWER: servants [accept attendants; accept domestic workers; accept maids; accept butlers; accept housekeepers; accept flunkies; accept word forms of all prior answers; prompt on subordinates; prompt on employees] <European History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Name this private historically black university in Alabama where George Washington Carver began his peanut experimentation to help sharecroppers. ","answer":"ANSWER: Tuskegee University [accept Tuskegee Institute National Historic Site] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] An investigation of experiments on syphilis performed on unknowing black sharecroppers resulted in the creation of this report, which defines modern guidelines on the ethical use of human subjects in research. ","answer":"ANSWER: Belmont Report "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Tuskegee’s campus was designed by Robert Taylor, whose son lends his name to the Robert Taylor Homes. Then the largest housing project in the U.S, the Homes were located in this city’s neighborhood of Bronzeville. ","answer":"ANSWER: Chicago <CE/Geo/Other/Pop Culture> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Name this autosomal disease that is most severe when 40 or more glutamine repeats are present in the mutated protein that causes it. Chorea (“kuh-REE-uh”) is a physical manifestation of this disease. ","answer":"ANSWER: Huntington’s disease [or Huntington’s chorea] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Huntington’s disease is caused by three repeating nucleobases: cytosine, adenine, and this nucleobase symbolized G. ","answer":"ANSWER: guanine "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Huntington’s disease and many trinucleotide repeat disorders exhibit this phenomenon, in which symptoms appear at an earlier age for each successive generation, possibly with an increase in severity. Myotonic dystrophy also displays this phenomenon. ","answer":"ANSWER: anticipation <Biology> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Name this novel by Leslie Marmon Silko in which the mixed-race Tayo battles PTSD from World War II and tries to reconnect with his indigenous ancestry. ","answer":"ANSWER: Ceremony "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] In Ceremony, Tayo returns home to one of these places after World War II. Louise Erdrich’s novel Love Medicine is set on one of these places home to the Ojibwe (“oh-JIB-way”) tribe. ","answer":"ANSWER: Native American reservations "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] In a poem from Ceremony, a grandmother who is one of these animals tells the Sun how to outsmart a gambler. Luis and Valentín are cellmates in a Manuel Puig (“pweeg”) novel whose title mentions this animal. ","answer":"ANSWER: spiders [accept araña; accept Spider Woman; accept Kiss of the Spider Woman] <World/Other Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Name this art movement whose derisive name was coined by Louis Vauxcelles (“voh-SELL”) to express his preference for a Donatello sculpture. Works in this style are characterized by their use of intense colors. ","answer":"ANSWER: Fauvism [or Les Fauves; or word forms] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] This leader of the Fauves painted The Dance and Woman with a Hat. He produced many cut-out collages later in life. ","answer":"ANSWER: Henri Matisse [or Henri Émile Benoît Matisse] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Fauvism member Maurice de Vlaminck painted a bright 1905 landscape set during this time. Vauxcelles coined the name of Fauvism at a 1905 salon named for this time period. ","answer":"ANSWER: autumn [accept fall; accept Autumn Landscape or Autumn Salon; accept Salon d’Automne] <Painting/Sculpture> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Name this midwestern state whose first-in-the-nation caucuses mark the beginning of the presidential primary season. ","answer":"ANSWER: Iowa "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Iowa has held the first Democractic primary since 1972, when the party’s primary system was overhauled by a commission co-chaired by this senator. He went on to win the 1972 Democratic nomination for president but lost to Richard Nixon. ","answer":"ANSWER: George McGovern "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] The closest ever Iowa caucus result occurred in 2012, when this former Pennsylvania senator defeated Mitt Romney by 34 votes. ","answer":"ANSWER: Rick Santorum <American History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Name this author who described child murders that match the plots of Katurian’s fairy tales in The Pillowman. This Irish playwright also wrote a trilogy set in the Aran (“AR-un”) Islands. ","answer":"ANSWER: Martin McDonagh (“muck-DON-uh”) "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Martin McDonagh wrote the screenplay to a dark comedy in which two members of this profession hide out in Bruges (“broozh”). In a play, two members of this profession argue about the phrases “light the kettle” and “put on the kettle.” ","answer":"ANSWER: hitmen [or paid assassins or hired killers; accept any answer indicating a person who kills people for money] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] The hitmen Gus and Ben receive instructions from the title device in this author’s play The Dumb Waiter. This British playwright also wrote The Birthday Party. ","answer":"ANSWER: Harold Pinter <British Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Name this physicist who also names a law stating that the closed line integral of the magnetic field is equal to permeability times the enclosed current. ","answer":"ANSWER: André-Marie Ampère "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] This term representing the time derivative of the electric flux density was added to Ampère’s law by James Clerk Maxwell. ","answer":"ANSWER: displacement current density [prompt on J-sub-D] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Maxwell’s equations unified magnetism and this phenomenon, which is caused by the presence of charged particles. ","answer":"ANSWER: electricity [accept electrostatics] <Physics> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Name this beautiful mortal man and lover of Aphrodite. Aphrodite asks him not to go out to hunt, but he does anyway and is killed by a wild boar. ","answer":"ANSWER: Adonis (The Hebrew word is Adonai.) "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Adonis was born out of a tree that used to be this woman. This woman was transformed into a tree as punishment for having sex with her father, King Cinyras (“sin-NYE-russ”). ","answer":"ANSWER: Myrrha [or Smyrna] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] In the Metamorphoses, the story of Adonis is framed as a song sung by this musician. This hero travels to the underworld to bring back his wife Eurydice (“yoo-RID-uh-see”), but he fails since he turns back to look at her. ","answer":"ANSWER: Orpheus <Mythology> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Name this broad art movement. The compositions of Claude Debussy and Maurice Ravel are considered exemplary of both symbolism and this later movement, despite their rejection of the label. ","answer":"ANSWER: impressionism [or word forms] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] In his study, Debussy kept a koto, a zither from this country. Its other folk instruments include a pear-shaped lute called biwa, an end-blown flute called shakuhachi (“sha-koo-HA-chee”), and a large drum called taiko. ","answer":"ANSWER: Japan [or Nippon-koku; or Nihon-koku] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] To evoke Eastern music, Debussy often used this symmetrical hexatonic scale. Since all of its notes are a major second apart, this scale lacks a leading tone and contains neither augmented intervals nor half steps. ","answer":"ANSWER: whole tone scale <Classical Music> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Name this country once led by Władysław Sikorski. This country’s President, Lech Kaczyński, also died in a similarly controversial plane crash in 2010 after taking off from his country’s capital, Warsaw. ","answer":"ANSWER: Poland [or Republic of Poland; or Polska] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] This statesman died in a 1961 plane crash while travelling to hold peace talks with Moïse Tshombe (“mo-EEZ CHOM-bay”). He was the only man to win the Nobel Peace Prize posthumously, and he succeeded Trygve Lie (“TRIG-vuh LEE”) to his most famous position. ","answer":"ANSWER: Dag Hammarskjöld (“dog HA-mar-hweld”) "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] In 2016, 64 members of this country’s premier military choir died after their plane crashed into the Black Sea. Aeroflot Flight 593 crashed in this country’s Kemerovo (“KAY-meh-ro-vuh”) Oblast after the pilot’s children accidentally disengaged the autopilot. ","answer":"ANSWER: Russia [or Russian Federation; or Rossiya] (The choir was called the Red Army Choir or Alexandrov Ensemble.) <European History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] This author described the structure as “sleepless as the river under thee” in the “Proem” that opens his long poem The Bridge. ","answer":"ANSWER: Hart Crane [or Harold Hart Crane] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] The speaker claims to be “the perfect man, the Buddha of This World” in this author’s unpublished “Brooklyn Bridge Blues.” This Beat author wrote about Sal Paradise in his novel On The Road. ","answer":"ANSWER: Jack Kerouac [or Jean-Louis Kérouac] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] This poet called the Brooklyn Bridge “Climactic ornament, a double rainbow” in the poem “Granite and Steel.” The speaker says, “I, too, dislike it” in this author’s poem “Poetry.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Marianne Moore [or Marianne Craig Moore] <American Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Name this property possessed by the products of asymmetric syntheses. Molecules with this property can rotate plane-polarized light. ","answer":"ANSWER: chirality (“kye-RAL-ity”) [or word forms; or optical activity] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] This scientist demonstrated chirality by showing that some crystals of a salt rotate light to the right while others rotate light to the left. The technique of heating milk to sterilize and extend shelf life is also named for this chemist. ","answer":"ANSWER: Louis Pasteur [accept pasteurization] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Pasteur used the enantiomers of this four-carbon molecule to demonstrate chirality. In the Sharpless epoxidation, an ester of this compound determines the stereochemistry of the product. ","answer":"ANSWER: tartaric acid [or diethyl tartrate or diisopropyl tartrate] <Chemistry> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Name this psychologist who discussed Abu Ghraib (“grayb”) in light of that experiment in The Lucifer Ef ect. His future wife Christina Maslach (“MAZZ-lock”) intervened and ended that unethical experiment after six days. ","answer":"ANSWER: Philip Zimbardo "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Ron Jones’s Third Wave Experiment was conducted in Palo Alto, which is home to this university. The Third Wave Experiment is often compared to Zimbardo’s “prison experiment” at this university. ","answer":"ANSWER: Stanford University "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] This Stanford graduate’s research on the “misinformation effect” has saved many from wrongful imprisonment on account of faulty eyewitness testimony. She co-developed the “Lost in the Mall” technique with James Coan (“KO-in”) to study false memories. ","answer":"ANSWER: Elizabeth Loftus <Social Science> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Name this West African empire founded by Sundiata Keita in the 13th century. It was later eclipsed by the Songhai Empire. ","answer":"ANSWER: Mali Empire [or Manden Kurufaba] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] This mansa of Mali legendarily caused the price of gold to plummet across the Middle East through the generosity he showed during a 1325 pilgrimage to Mecca. ","answer":"ANSWER: Mansa Musa [or Musa Keita I] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Description acceptable. Mansa Musa took power after his predecessor, Abu Bakr II, supposedly disappeared while trying to perform this action. Rutgers professor Ivan Van Sertima tried to prove that Abu Bakr succeeded in this action by cherry-picking passages from Bartolomé de las Casas. ","answer":"ANSWER: crossing the Atlantic ocean [accept descriptive equivalents indicating that Abu Bakr disappeared in the course of exploring the ocean; accept discovering the Americas or discovering the New World or equivalents; accept sailing west] <World History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Name this religious identity that characterized the domestic life of Sabbatai Zevi’s (“SHAH-beh-tye ts’VEE’s”) Dönmeh community in the Ottoman Empire. A solitary community of these people in Belmonte (“bel-MON-tih”) embodied the idea of the “Crypto” type of them. ","answer":"ANSWER: they were Jews [accept Jewishness or word forms; accept believers in Judaism; accept Crypto-Jews; prompt on hiding one’s religion or hiding one’s faith by asking “which faith were they hiding?”; prompt on not actually being Christian or Muslim] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] This Spanish term referred to people who continued to practice Judaism secretly, even after forced conversion to Christianity. While originally an insult, many Jews later adopted this term in honor, explaining its etymology via their dietary habits. ","answer":"ANSWER: marranos [prompt on conversos] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] This term refers to the Jewish ethnic group originally from Spain and Portugal; they constitute the majority of European Jews along with the Ashkenazi. ","answer":"ANSWER: Sephardic Jews [or Sephardim] <Religion> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Name these discrete models that consist of grids of elements, with each element in one of a finite set of states and surrounded by a “neighborhood,” that progresses through “generations” under a mathematically defined rule. ","answer":"ANSWER: cellular automaton [accept tessellation automaton; accept automata in place of “automaton”; prompt on automaton; prompt on CA] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Natural cellular automata often generate these infinitely self-similar curves that appear to be the same upon successive magnifications. Examples of these curves include the Menger (“MENG-er”) sponge and the Sierpinski carpet. ","answer":"ANSWER: fractal curves "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] This Yale mathematician coined the term “fractal,” one of which can be formed by his namesake set. His most famous paper discusses a paradox regarding the length of Britain’s coastline. ","answer":"ANSWER: Benoit B. Mandelbrot [accept Mandelbrot set] (The “B.” does not stand for anything.) <Other Science> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Name this analytical Thomist (“TOM-ist”) who introduced the term “consequentialism” in the paper “Modern Moral Philosophy.” This student of Ludwig Wittgenstein is credited with reviving virtue ethics in that paper. ","answer":"ANSWER: G. E. M. Anscombe [or Gertrude Elizabeth Margaret Anscombe] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] This early text includes practical wisdom, or phronesis (“fro-NEE-sis”), as one of the five intellectual virtues. It asserts that the highest good is a state of “energeic” happiness called eudaimonia (“yoo-da-MO-nee-uh”). ","answer":"ANSWER: Nicomachean Ethics "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Phillipa Foot’s neo-Aristotelian virtue ethics have been overshadowed by her invention of this dilemma. It asks if you should pull a lever to make the namesake vehicle run over only one person, rather than five. ","answer":"ANSWER: trolley problem <Philosophy> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Bohumil Hrabal used just a single 128-page sentence for his novel Dancing Lessons for the Advanced in Age, which he wrote in this language. Tomáš and Tereza’s dog Karenin dies of cancer in another novel in this language. ","answer":"ANSWER: Czech (The second novel is Milan Kundera’s The Unbearable Lightness of Being.) "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] This author wrote a ten-page sentence about the history of the Theresienstadt (“tuh-RAY-zin-shtott”) ghetto in his novel Austerlitz. This author intersperses photographs throughout his novels, which include The Emigrants and The Rings of Saturn. ","answer":"ANSWER: W. G. Sebald "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Polish author Jerzy Andrzejewski (“YEHR-zhih on-dray-YEFF-skee”) used only two sentences, the second of which is four words, in his novel The Gates of this location. John Milton wrote an epic titled this location Lost. ","answer":"ANSWER: paradise [accept The Gates of Paradise or Paradise Lost] <European Literature>"}]
